# **Anthony Kolade**

#### UX Consultant at DGtal-Mind

## Summary

I am a graduate of Fine-Arts, Textile Design and Technology and a multi-skilled matured individual with a wealth of experience that stretches from self-employment to senior retail management, digital design, development and marketing and to UX designing. I have worked for large companies such as SSP-UK (Select Service Partners), Marks and Spencer, Matalan and Makro where I progressed to become senior retail manager before career change to digital design.

I have worked on variety of digital projects including logo and banner designs, static, interactive and ecommerce website designs and development, front-end designs, E-Mail design and development, SEO and Analytics and now progressed to providing UX solutions.

# Experience

#### UX Consultant at DGtal-Mind Limited

November 2015 - Present (1 year 5 months)

DGtal-Mind, my 'one man band' start-up digital agency helps businesses of all sizes from start-ups to big brands, charities, and social enterprise to create outstanding user-centred experience.

#### **UX Designer at IROKO Theatre Company**

January 2015 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Working closely with executives to define requirements and produced comprehensive, detailed development documentation

including functional requirements, site maps, process flows, and page schematics.

\* Providing visual designs of final interface including storyboards, sketches and low and hi-fidelity wireframes of core user journeys,

landing and sub-pages.

\* Working alongside team of software developers and business analysts in an agile environment to improve user friendliness and

accessibility with the implementation.

#### Consultant at MyCompleteFocus CIC

2015 - 2016 (1 year)

#### Design Consultant at Cross Technologies Ltd

January 2009 - January 2014 (5 years 1 month)

Cross Technologies Ltd is a media consultancy agency with focus on Media, Marketing, and Brand Management where I had the opportunity to work on various media projects including:

- YS Technologies Ltd | www.ystechnologies.com.ng
- Aksotech Ltd | www.aksotech.com.ng
- Kenya High Commission | www.kenyanigeria.org
- Taimez Limited | www.taimez.com

#### **Duties:**

- Ongoing design and maintenance of new and existing websites.
- Liaised closely with customers and clients at the design stages.
- Promotion of websites using Google Adwords, and SEOGears.
- Interact with designers, programmers and clients.
- Enhancing the look, functionality and appearance of websites.
- Fixed problems encountered in the functioning of websites.
- Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives, editorials, emails & Designed web campaigns for online initiatives were designed with the design for online initiatives were designed with the design of the design
- Build affiliate white-labels websites, promotional banners & Damp; creative materials.
- Test websites for functionality in different browsers & Dry; at different resolutions.

#### MD/CEO at Cross Technologies Ltd, Nigeria

2013 - 2013 (less than a year)

#### Senior Retail Manager at SSP, Marks and Spencer, Matalan and Makro

January 2003 - January 2009 (6 years 1 month)

#### Responsibilities:

I was responsible for overall organization, sales and profitability by providing clear leadership to my management team to maximise profitability, via the implementation of the Cluster's Business Plan, by delivering outstanding levels of service to all customers, in the most cost effective manner whilst ensuring policy compliance.

#### Achievements:

Achieved 70%, exceeded 25% and improved upon 5% of all set targets and KPIs.

# Volunteer Experience

#### Website Consultant at Total Parental Guidance Orphanage

#### February 2010 - Present

Planned, Designed, and Developed their website as donation to the orphanage.

Also I have been maintaining the site since then till date.

# Skills & Expertise

**User Experience** 

**Information Architecture** 

Wireframes

**Usability** 

**Personas** 

User scenarios,

**Task Flows** 

**Storyboards** 

**Taxonomies** 

**Site Maps** 

**Mockups** 

Low and high fidelity mockups on paper

Tree testing

**Focus Groups** 

**Guerrilla User Testing** 

**Lab Testing** 

**Prototypes** 

**Photoshop** 

Web Design

Digital Design, Development and Marketing

HTML Email Designing, Development and

Marketing

HTML5

**SEO** 

**Web Analytics** 

**Google Analytics** 

**CMS** 

**CSS** 

**Business Planning** 

**Project Management** 

**Business Strategy** 

**Strategic Planning** 

Windows

**Microsoft Office** 

Leadership

**Storyboarding** 

Management

**User Experience Design** 

### Education

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Textile and Knitwear Technology, 1990 - 1994

The Polytechnic, Ibadan, Nigeria.

O.N.D and H.N.D, Fine Arts and Textile Design, 1981 - 1987

Loyola College, Ibadan, Nigeria

## Interests

I enjoy regular workouts. Eating out to have a tasting experience of various delicacies in town and visit the cinema whenever time permits. I am keen to keep up to date with the latest UX and Design news.

# **Anthony Kolade**

UX Consultant at DGtal-Mind



Contact Anthony on LinkedIn